All right. Is everybody here?
I think we'll go ahead and get started.
If anyone joins late, that's fine.
I hope the best consulting team in the
world had a great weekend.
So late last week,
I was able to meet with a client and I
wanted to bring back kind of the,
what I heard from them.
So this client wants an app to help with
weight loss.
So it's a very ambiguous goal.
They did say that I...
Ideally,
iPhone and Android support at some point,
but we can go one by one if we want.
And they did seem like open to our
recommendations on which ones to tackle
first.
So if we wanted to do like an MVP or a V1
and like just one thing,
like I think they seemed open to that.
And.
their feelings were, you know, with,
I don't know,
GLP of ones and everything else going on,
there's this just big surge in interest
and a huge market for weight loss apps
right now.
So they really wanted to get in on that
market and are paying for us to create a
weight loss app for them.
I'm personally worried that it's a pretty
saturated market.
But that's what the client is asking for.
So that's what we're going to do.
So we will need to figure out how to
differentiate from all the other weight
loss apps that are on the market right
now.
Helping with weight loss is like such an
ambiguous goal.
There's so many ways that we could do
this. There's, you know, calorie counters,
there's activity trackers,
that do things like biking and yoga and
everything else.
There's actual steps counters.
There's like logging your weight
explicitly, logging your food,
designing workouts.
There's offering personalized advice.
There's tracking all those other things
that can contribute to weight loss,
like sleep and water intake and stress.
There are so many existing fitness apps
out there,
so integration might be helpful.
So like there was just so many ideas.
So what I want this meeting to be is a
brainstorming meeting for us to figure
out like how we want to tackle this and
then we can bring that back to the client.
So let me open the floor for ideas of
what you guys think we should do and how
we could how we could get started with
this. Any thoughts?
One thing I want to raise before we get
into brainstorming is just the last
project,
the privacy review came very late in the
process and we had all that scramble.
So I'd really like us to think about
privacy up front here when we, you know,
maybe not right first thing with
brainstorming, but as
in the early stage of the process,
so we don't have that scramble at the end.
No, privacy will be important.
That makes sense,
especially if it's logging things like my
weight. I don't want that leaking.
So got it. So great point, Alex.
Any other thoughts that people have about
like how we should even get started on
this? This is such a huge project.
Does anyone? Oh yeah, okay. Yeah.
Oh, go ahead.
So I think we need to start with a really
clear business model.
So how are we going to make money and how
are we going to identify what's our
target market?
Because as you mentioned earlier,
it's massively saturated and there's some
established players.
And in order for us to take market share,
we're going to need to spend some serious
marketing dollars.
and we're going to want to be thoughtful
about our channel marketing and who we
partner if we do partnerships.
So there's just a lot of different
factors,
but we should be really crisp on our
business model so that we're not throwing
money out towards something that's not
going to get the returns.
Yeah.
Yeah,
we should also like consider if there's a
segment of the market we're going to go
after.
We don't have to go after obviously
everyone, but a particular,
I don't even really know what the weight
loss market looks like,
but I imagine there's a portion of that
we could go after.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
saturated market over all of the other
ones.
Yeah.
I like that idea of maybe choosing a
target audience. Like if we focus on just,
I don't know, senior citizens or like,
or people over 50 or just, you know,
men or just women or, you know,
something like that. If we carve out a,
that niche,
maybe that would help us differentiate
well. So that's a good idea.
We probably need to do more research
there.
On, like,
what the what the markets look like and
what the business,
the best business opportunity is, um, but.
Yeah,
do we have any foregoing research or is
..
we kind of coming in fresh to this?
We're coming in fresh.
Like all I have is what the client gave
me and honestly, you know, they don't,
they clients never know what they want.
K.
So I think we have to do a lot of
research and present to them like, here's,
here's what we think you should do in the
aspects that we do.
So maybe we could start up some research
processes going right shortly after this
to kind of figure out what the market
looks like right now and where the best
business opportunity is.
I think given that I would love to see,
you know, as part of that market study,
not only understanding what is a segment,
but what in that segment,
what kinds of apps do they typically
stick with and do they typically use,
Yeah.
right? So what are like, for example,
the top 10 apps that if we, for example,
target, you know, an older
crew, like an older segment, you know,
for example,
Yeah.
is Duolingo something that they really
are interested in or other types of apps
that are really sticky that kind of keep
them coming back?
Because I think coming back to also
Sarah's point of how do we make money?
I mean,
I wonder if there's sort of that freemium
aspect that we think about.
where you start,
where you kind of draw people in,
but then you create that that desire for
them to keep coming back.
We want to think about like daily active
users and then weekly active users and
then monthly active users and some of the
best ways to do that and create like
create that kind of stickiness.
is like creating streaks, right? Like, oh,
hey, you get,
you every day you log back in,
something is great. Or as we think about,
you know, how do we.
Maybe it's even push notifications.
How do we bring people back every day?
Yeah.
Because once we show that we had like
help the customer or the client bring
customers back and like they'll keep
growing users, right?
Because they'll see those,
the Dao metrics keep growing and growing
and growing, hopefully.
Yeah, that's a great point. I saw,
I have something to say,
but I saw Idan has his hand up.
So why don't you go first? Oh, me first?
Okay. I love that idea, Weiwei, honestly.
I definitely think the freemium model is
good because we can hopefully get a large,
you know,
a bunch of downloads by having a free app
and make it easier to get in people's
hands.
And then when you think about like,
there's so much we could do with AI here.
So maybe some of these AI features,
which are going to be more expensive for
us because we have to call whatever
models to do it, maybe those are upsells.
So things like, I don't know,
taking a picture of your food and using
AI to convert it.
to a food log with calories and all the
other macros that people care. Protein,
all I hear about at my age is protein for
women.
You need to be eating protein 24-7 or
else you're going to die. And then,
I don't know,
AI to personalize your workout routine or
AI to recommend healthier food swaps.
So think about like if I'm doing
mayonnaise on my
you know,
swapping mayonnaise for Greek yogurt or
whatever,
that's those kind of things that an AI
could recommend.
And that could potentially be an upsell.
I don't know. I'm sorry, go ahead. Idan,
what was your point?
So, you know,
in information that will shock you all,
I'm like super into like devices.
And I have to wonder if maybe that's good
on both the business level and on the
go-to-market level,
like focusing on the kinds of people that
have devices.
that are very into the whole quantified
self thing.
These are the people that are gonna turn
around and they're gonna make noise on
social and whatever about like, you know,
like, hey,
I like added this app to my life and it
had all this impact and here I've got
charts and blah, blah, blah. So like,
they're a good set of early adopters.
It also is like, you know,
a watch on my wrist is a device that's
constantly in my face,
even when I'm like working out.
It's not like, you know,
I pull out my phone on the treadmill.
And thirdly,
like maybe from a revenue perspective,
you know,
we can get into like recurring revenue
territory by doing deals with like the
hardware providers of the whatevers.
and that'll be attractive because it's
not just like, okay,
I buy a subscription and it's just
software in the cloud,
but like if I buy the watch,
it comes like six months with the watch
or a year with the watch or I don't know,
like there's room there to like dip into
Oh, I like that. Yeah.
more than one pool of money.
That's a great idea.
That's cool.
We should think more about that
Yeah.
integration. Go ahead.
I see Alex has his hand up though.
Yeah, I mean,
I think these are all really good ideas.
As we think about it, let's also...
be thinking about what kind of data we
can ask for from people and how that data
is secured so that data that people might
not want to share out on social or
wherever doesn't leak out sort of
unexpectedly.
Like if you remember earlier in Strava's
history,
the some of the soldiers at a base in
like Afghanistan or somewhere were
logging their runs,
which seemed perfectly fine from an
individual standpoint, but as a group,
then some of that was public and so then.
people, adversaries,
whoever could see like where this base
They figured out the soldiers. Oh no.
was. So, you know,
this is like that situation is not going
My gosh.
to happen with our weight loss app,
but let's be aware of things that sort of
unanticipated issues with the data if it
is shared publicly.
Yeah, no, there definitely is. Like,
I don't think the data should be shared
publicly,
but I do agree that there's all of those
things. Like,
so weight in itself can be a sensitive
topic,
but there's a whole bunch of other things
that factor into weight loss that we
might want to ask people,
like your age matters for how, you know,
a 20 year old loses weight different than
a 50 year old.
And same thing with gender, right?
The way women and men lose weight is
different too. So like,
I think we need to ask for a whole lot of
PII and we'll have to make sure that that
data is secured.
Yeah,
and let's check with the privacy folks
about what we can reasonably ask for and
what we can't.
There might be things like gender or
whatever that there, I don't know,
Okay. Okay.
there just might be restrictions.
We just check on that before we build it
into the plan.
Okay, got it. Sarah has her hand up next.
Yeah,
one of the things that I don't think I'm
super clear on is the company, the client.
Like what else do they do?
Because from a business perspective,
an app does not create a business.
Like you're not just really going to
drive enough revenue to probably really
expand and grow.
So what is this app a gateway into?
Like do they offer?
some sort of other product that we're
trying to create? Like,
are we actually just using the app as a
front door for actually selling something
else? Like,
should we partner with a pharmaceutical
company who's selling GLPs and this app
is like actually driving people to
purchase the GLP or a wearable or some
sort of, you know, is it a physical,
like a product, like clothing or whatnot?
But I think just as a standalone app,
Yeah.
there are so many out there.
there unless we're just re-skinning like
Noom or one of the many others that are
there,
we're not going to really differentiate
ourselves.
That is an excellent question, Sarah.
I did not get that information from the
client at this point. What he seemed,
it seemed like they were a very rich
person who was into bodybuilding and
wanted,
had enough money to throw at our
consulting company to build this for them.
But maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe there is something else in this
backstory that I hadn't thought through.
So let, do you, yeah, I'm not 100% sure.
I'll ask,
I'll make a note to follow up with the
client on that.
I think that helps us, but yeah.
Jen,
I love that information because I feel
like, sorry, my cat just attacked me.
Now it's on the recording.
But in any case,
what I was thinking was like, for example,
if this is around bodybuilding, you know,
like what is our MVP, right?
Like what are we,
what are we proposing as a first?
build,
if this is indeed related to what the
client specifically wants. I think,
you know,
because as I consider what a first launch
might be, you know,
what is a scenario that we're enabling,
what is a use case that we're enabling,
and how do we kind of bring, again,
and maybe I'm going to harp on it a
little bit.
How do we bring people back, right?
Because I think there's definitely like
the weight loss app or that concept of if,
again, if it's towards bodybuilding,
Consistency is key.
how do we think about...
getting you like,
I think there might be already be an
incentive if you're targeting like a
certain, you know, muscle ratio,
body fat ratio.
Like how do you get the users to want to
keep participating in that, right?
Because you know,
as they're doing weigh-ins,
as they're doing these other things like
Yeah.
every day check-in.
Yeah.
We might need a...
Yeah.
somehow understands,
because I'm doing it every day,
Yeah.
that you can see the change over time.
Yeah, we...
Yeah,
we might need to partner with like a
smart scale type company if we wanted to
get that body composition info.
So that's another great part.
Alex has a point and then after he's done,
I'm going to suggest,
I wonder if we should start thinking
about like the UI for let's so so the end
goal and here's a UI and like when I open
up the app,
like what is the experience and what what
kind of things do we need in the MVP?
Like.
I think weight tracking,
if the end goal is to lose weight,
the first thing we need to log is weight,
right?
Because we need to see if that's tracking
down.
But then there may be other things as
well. So like,
what would that UI look like?
Would it be like a journey type thing,
like Duolingo?
Would it be just like a table almost of
your weight?
Would it be a graph showing the up and
down movement?
Maybe let's start thinking about like
what is it that we want to show and what
needs to be an MVP. All right, sorry,
Alex, I know you had your hand up.
Yeah, I mean,
my point goes right along with what you
were saying, but though, because like,
sort of you can have like weight loss is
maybe an end goal, you know,
but then how do you make a sort of a
maintenance be a compelling experience?
It's sort of not quite as exciting as
accomplishing a goal, you know,
staying at it.
at a state is harder to gamify or to like
motivate people.
So I think how we think about.
incenting people to come back and stay
engaged even after they reach one goal.
But also, obviously,
we're not driving people to lose weight
endlessly.
So I feel like that could be just a
Yeah.
challenge with the mentality about coming
back.
Em.
I don't have an answer just raising that
as an issue.
That's a great point.
So maybe people have a target weight then.
So maybe the initial, like,
I hate to say it,
like unboxing experience,
that's not the right word,
but I'm thinking of my kids.
But the initial experience,
like when you first log in and create an
account, maybe you put like your,
I enter my, you know, my name,
my current weight,
and my height or whatever,
and then the app can help calculate,
and I guess your gender might be needed,
and maybe the app can calculate like what
a good BMI is for you,
and then you can choose something in that
range, or I don't know,
or we just let the person
put in their own target weight.
So that way we do have that nice ending
thing.
And then we could have a fireworks
graphic when they make it or something
fun like that, something to celebrate.
I love onboarding experiences.
They are what help get you into that sort
of like,
that retention period of now that you've
Okay.
put it in, now do it again.
Now do it again. That's how you get them.
Yeah.
Okay.
The other thing too is like,
and I know Alex will probably have
something to say about AI and the risks
here,
but there's so much that we're seeing
about AI being able to catch markers and
signals of your health in different ways
than we've not thought about before.
So what can the app do that's
sophisticated enough to offer something
unique and different than what the
current market has? So again,
it's about how we differentiate.
pick our target customer,
market segmentation,
and then what information can the app
capture and what can we build out?
There's so much biometric data available.
So I really think that we need to partner
with some sort of,
either it's a wearable or something else
besides just an app that's like doing
calorie counting,
because that's not unique and new enough
to the market.
Got it. Okay.
So I think there's two areas of research
that we need to tackle after this meeting.
Number one is like,
what is the best target market for this?
Number 2 is potential partners,
especially in the hardware thing,
smart watches, heart trackers,
stress trackers,
like all of the great stuff, smart scales,
stuff that's out there already so we can
figure out
integration.
So I think those are two research jobs to
be done.
And then given all like what we know
right now,
is there anything else like we'll come
back and adjust the plan once we have
that research. But like right now,
the minimum.
like an MVP for success.
Let's kind of throw out like what that
might look like and we can put out like
UX as well, but like exit criteria,
I guess.
Like what are the things where like at
minimum we need to be tracking weight
because the end goal is weight loss.
And then I think we need all those things
that I mentioned in the onboarding
section kind of.
part of like,
here's the stuff we need to know to help
make good decisions.
Is there any other data we need or
thoughts on like the UI and like what
after that onboarding experience,
like what should the screen show or what
could we,
how could we kind of motivate them to
take the next step?
Is AI suggesting a next step given?
you know, your lifestyle.
I guess that's another thing that matters
if you work behind a desk versus you're
on your feet all day. So like,
what are all those things that we should
be gathering and then how do we, yeah.
I, I...
I think AI could suggest some goals.
I think we definitely want the user,
I think we should be framed as a
suggestion though, not like, hey,
we've analyzed you,
this is what you should do.
Like we need to make sure the user feels
in control of their journey and can.
Finalize on the goals they're going after.
Right. If it's AI,
we should definitely have it as a
suggestion anyway and also explicitly let
them know where AI is used in the app.
Yeah, exactly.
That should always be presented to the
user. I agree with that.
So when I think about what's the unique
like...
quality of AI when it comes to these
kinds of things is it's sort of like one
or two things that jumps out at me.
The first is it's not a human.
I feel less embarrassed in front of the
AI because it's not, it's like,
That good, really good point.
That's a really good point.
and this is a sensitive topic.
Nobody wants to be like, man,
I feel overweight and like,
I don't want to talk about this with
other people, but.
maybe it's okay because the robot doesn't
judge me.
It just keeps being chipper and telling
me like, okay, like you're going to do it.
Today's the day or whatever it is that it
does. So really leaning into that.
Yeah.
The other aspect is, of course, you know,
airing my dirty laundry to the AI in the
form of like, here's all the data.
Like, yes, I work behind a desk.
That's not going to change. Like,
you know,
this product is not going to suddenly
Right.
change my job, my life, my whatever. So,
but instead leaning into like,
this product takes you as you are and
helps you find opportunities that fit
into your life.
That's the emotional heart of this
product to me.
Yeah.
Mhm.
Maybe,
maybe that could be like the next step
that like Weiwei was talking about or
something that makes it sticky and come
back to you.
Maybe every day it has a new suggestion
I like that title for the app or the name,
the next step that we can name it that.
for you.
The next step, that is a good title.
I love that. Great idea. But like...
Like day one,
it's just like drink more water kind of
deal or like something that's pretty easy.
And then every day you add on another
step towards your weight loss journey,
that would make it sticky.
Mm-hmm.
And then there's a new suggestion every
day.
So you're motivated to come back and get
the suggestion every day. Oh,
I think Nadia, her hand is up.
Do you want to say what you were thinking
about, Nadia?
I couldn't come up with a good persona.
I got way too nervous.
So I just typed in the chat. No,
I was just thinking about like the
integration component of it, right?
Like the stuff that we mentioned.
What if it can already pull from the
stuff that people are using and then a
way to enhance the gamification, right?
Because I might not want to lose my
streaks in MyFitnessPal and Duolingo and
whatever else I'm using.
So if it can pull that in automatically,
that helps and also prevents me from
feeling like I have to set up yet another
thing, even if I want to use this app.
But then if we want to keep that
distinguishing appeal of the app and the
gamification aspect,
maybe we can do something different where
it gives you some kind of quirky feedback.
And the example that I used in the chat
was people who don't want to see their
numbers or who can't see their numbers,
if they're like,
I don't know,
numbers of verse or recovering from like
a...
health issue,
that it could do something fun, like, oh,
Mhm.
you've drank as much water as it rained
into the Sara today,
or like you have the muscle mass of a
cheetah.
Uh-huh.
It's like a gamification thing for the
people who don't have an issue with the
That's awesome.
numbers,
but can also provide obfuscation for the
people who can't see numbers every day or
who that's dangerous for in whatever way.
I love that.
Yeah.
I love that.
So I thought like that could be a fun way
to fit a lot of the AI components and the
integration components we've been talking
about,
but also add to the whole like experience,
uniqueness of what we're building.
And obviously, Weiwei was right.
I love gamification.
So anything in that vein, I mean.
That is so cool. I love that suggestion.
You've lost as much weight as a bunch of
I... yeah, I'm gonna...
So.
grapes. That's such a good idea.
So that one I stole because I was
thinking like the pregnancy apps do this
thing where they're like,
your baby is the size of a mango.
And it's like so weird. But like,
so what's the positive opposite of that,
Yeah.
right?
And then the like my fitness water water,
Yeah!
you're not a cactus always refers to like
deserts and rainforests.
Like what are the cool things we can
tweak from those existing apps,
Yeah.
but put them all together. So like,
you don't know what this app is going to
tell you today,
but it's going to tell you something cool
about your journey.
And you're going to go back because it's
kind of like what the forecast,
if you all have ever used this for
weather,
even if you don't need to know the
weather,
you're opening that up because you want
to see what kind of ridiculous **** it
I...
says today.
So like it could have that aspect.
Nadia, you,
I just want to kind of bring up the fact
that we've said journey quite a few times.
And, you know,
Yeah, we have.
and if we call it the next step,
like I feel like it almost sounds like a
game to me, like a journey,
like every day you're kind of true,
like you take the next step into another
part.
Of something.
and like as a visual, right?
Because then you feel like though that
Mmh.
you've stepped in,
like there's something new that you see
Yeah.
every day, just like Nadia said,
like your little avatar is in a new place
because you've taken the next step on
your weight loss journey.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
And not only that,
you've discovered that like grapes,
I've lost grapes. I've lost a mango.
I've lost a whole watermelon.
Yeah.
Alright, that's so...
I'm a big proponent of like cozy gaming
too.
So like the whole like Stardew Valley is
all the type of vibes and like, oh,
if you could do this,
this could be more fun. But yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I feel like there's a lot of weight loss
apps right now with like a little avatar
or a little cartoon character that's like
urging you on or whatever,
some kind of little thingy to be
encouraging. That's so interesting. Okay,
well, I see we're about at time.
We definitely have more research to do.
And I think the next step is probably to
take all these requirements and build
them into a spec,
and then we can get implementing after
that.
Does anyone have any final thoughts they
want to share before we conclude on other
requirements we might have missed or
Is that?
Jake.
thoughts you have?
Jennifer,
is that action item on you then to build
that spec or are you looking for someone
else to do that?
Are you creating a shared space for us to
plan?
I think the next step is that we have an
agent try to build the app,
Who?
the spec from this. All right? Wonderful.
All right. So cool. All right. Well,
Sounds great. That sounds perfect.
Love it.
thank you guys so much for this great
brainstorming.
and I can't wait to see like what we
build.
We'll check in again at tomorrow's stand
up. Take care.
Hi.